Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Senior Prize Essays
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- History senior essay prize winners, 2009; Accession 2010-A-012
  - History of Science/History of Medicine Prize, 2009
    - Martin Klein and George Rosen Prize, 2009
      - Anna Legant Parks, "Polio Across the Iron Curtain: Dorothy M. Horstmann's 1959 Evaluation ofthe Sabin Polio Vaccine Trial in the U.S.S.R."; advisor: Bruno Strasser, 2009
        General note
        See: Box 1, folder 4
  - Outside Department Prizes, 2009
    - The David M. Potter Prize (from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library for an outstanding essay in American History or Culture), 2009
      - Anna Legant Parks, "Polio Across the Iron Curtain:Dorothy M. Horstmann's 1959 Evaluation of the Sabin Polio Vaccine Trial in the U.S.S.R"; advisor: Professor Bruno Strasser, 2009
        See: Box 1, Folder 4
    - The Walter McClintock Prize 2008-2009 Academic Year (from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library for the Best Essay on the History or Culture of Native Americans)
      - Christine Glandorf, "The Miseducation of Benjamin Larnell: The Story of the Last Indian Student at Colonial Harvard"; advisor: Professor Keith Wrightson, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - The Howard R. Lamar Prize 2008-2009 Academic Year (from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library in the History or Culture of the American West)
      - Christopher Adler, "The Myth of Jesse James in Early American Film: The Many Masks of the World's Most Famous Outlaw"; advisor: Professor Alyssa Mt. Pleasant, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - The American Jewish Congress Prize 2008-2009 Academic Year (from the Religious Studies Program)
      - Benjamin Tannen, "The Transformation of the American JewishA gricultural Movement from New Odessa to Woodbine"; advisor: Professor Paula Hyman, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Beth Reisfeld,"LUCY DAWIDOWICZ: AN AMERICAN IN THE JERUSALEM OF LITHUANIA"; advisor: Professor Marci Shore, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Williams Prize 2008-2009 Academic Year (from The Council on East Asian Studies For an Outstanding Essays on a Chinese, Japanese or Korean Subject)
      - Xidi Liu, "From Privatization to Nationalization-The Bank of China from 1912 to 1937"; advisor: Professor Peter C. Perdue, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Lauren Bias," Pan-Asianism: Resistance and Adaptation During the Japanese Occupation of Southeast Asia 1940-1945"; advisor: Professor Benedict Kiernan, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - The Manuscripts and Archives Prize (for outstanding research done in Manuscripts and Archives), 2009
      - Kevin Michel, "A Reexamination of the Idea of a Cohesive Conservative Movement Through the Intellectual Life and Personal Conflict Surrounding L. Brent Bozell"; advisor: Professor Beverly Gage, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2010; Accession 2010-A-087; 1; (2 boxes)
  - American Prizes
    - George Washington Egleston Prize
      - Baumgartner, Alice Lucile, "The Rivers of America: The History of Naming and the Memory of Names from John Smith to Constance Lindsay Skinner;" advisor: Jay Gitlin., 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - John Addison Porter Prize
      - Gitlin, Basie Bales, "Great Readers of Men: Subscription Book Agents, the Selling of Culture, and the Culture of Selling in America, 1865-1935;" advisor: Joanne Freeman, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Edwin W. Small Prize
      - Tumeh, Lara Christine, "The Integration of Women into All-Male Social Clubs in New York City: Local Law 63 and the Century Association;" advisor: Cynthia Russett., 2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Gilliland, Jason Wansley, "The Calculus of Realignment: The Rise of Republicanism in Georgia, 1964-1992;" advisor: Glenda Gilmore., 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Percival Wood Clement Prize
      - Yu, Lea Sia, "Lest They Fall Into Wayward Company;" advisor: Beverly Gage., 2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Verkamp, Casey Leigh, "K.C. Li and U.S. Tungsten Supplies for WW II: A Chinese-American Alloy of Power;" advisor: Adam Tooze, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Andrew D. White American Prize
      - Hamstra, David Daniel, "'Lonesome George' Romney and the Perils of Political Independence;" advisor: Beverly Gage, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Olivarius-McAllister, Chase Beckley, "The Amistad, Camelot, Jerusalem, and Dred Scott;" advisor: David Blight, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Ramey, Alexander Edward, "Reality and Remembrance: Theodore Roosevelt and the Anthracite Coal Strike of 1902;" advisor: Cynthia Russett, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Walton, Alice Fyffe, "Victory Gardens in New York City During World War II: Planting Patriotism;" advisor: Paul Sabin, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History of Science/History of Medicine Prize
    - Martin Klein and George Rosen Prize
      - Newman, Kira, "Shutt Up: Bubonic Plague and Quarantine in Early Modem England;" advisor: Keith Wrightson, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - European Prizes
    - Winifred Sturley Prize
      - Johnson, Berit Allison "Coventry Cathedral: The November 14, 1940 Destruction, the Decision to Rebuild, and the Consecration of the New Cathedral In 1962;" advisor: Jay Winter, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Watson, Amy Elizabeth, "The Sexual Politics of Anti-Dissenting Literature In Mid-to-Late Seventeenth-Century England: Whores, Cuckolds, and Libertines;" advisor: Steven Pincus, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Andrew D. White European Prize
      - Gentele, Noah Ziggy, "The Format of the West: Napoleon's France, Historiale, and the Systematic Self Consciousness of British Modernity;" advisor: Steven Pincus, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Mezger, Caroline Eva, "Limbo Exodus: The Expulsion of Ethnic Germans from Central and Eastern Europe around the Close of WW II;" advisor: Adam Tooze, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rest of the World Prizes
    - Max Bildner Prize
      - Long, Matthew Posler, "The Miraculous Nation: Religion, Print Culture and the Development of a National Consciousness in Colonial Mexico;" advisor: Stuart Schwartz, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Novas, Mariel Mercedes, "Dominican Transnationality, Diasporic Identity and Cultural Production in Early Twentieth Century Dominican Republic and Early Twenty-First Century Spain;" advisor: Stephen Pitti, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Saetveit, Kristin Leanna, '"Towards an Indian Dawn': Reconfiguring Ethnicity in the Guatemalan Civil War;" advisor: Gilbert Joseph, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Robert D. Gries Prize
      - Hefferon, Lauren Elizabeth, "Women's Suffrage in Mexico: Winning the Vote in a Context of Gender Inequality and Imperfect Democracy;" advisor: Gilbert Joseph, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Andrew D. White Rest of the World Prize
      - Gant, Philip Alexander, "Expert Remembering: Cultural Heritage and the Rise of the Chogye Order of Korean Buddhism in the 1960s;" advisor: Peter C. Perdue, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Iscoe, Mark Samuel, "Chester Bowles in India: A Defender of Freedom;" advisor: Mridu Rai, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Porter, David Campbell, "The Manchu Version of Chinese Nationalism;" advisor: Peter C. Perdue, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Outside Department Prizes
    - The Williams Prize (from the Council on East Asian Studies)
      - Gant, Philip Alexander, "Expert Remembering: Cultural Heritage and the Rise of the Chogye Order of Korean Buddhism in the 1960s;" advisor: Peter C. Perdue, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Porter, David Campbell, "The Manchu Version of Chinese Nationalism;" advisor: Peter C. Perdue, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Thornton, Michael, "Japanese Encounters with the Muslim World at the Turn of the Twentieth Century: Transnational Subversion and Global Power;" advisor: Fabian Drixler, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - The Walter McClintock Prize (from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library)
      - Pearl, Stephanie Elise, "The Genizara Experience in Eighteenth-Century New Mexico: Creating and Defending an Identity from the Confines of Social Captivity;" advisor: Professor Ned Blackhawk, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Howard Lamar Prize (from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library)
      - Wu, Victoria, "The War for the American Southwest, 1861-1865: The Famished Country;" advisor: Professor John Mack Faragher, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Potter Prize (from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library)
      - Gitlin, Basie Bales, "Great Readers of Men: Subscription Book Agents, the Selling of Culture, and the Culture of Selling in America, 1865-1935;" advisor: Joanne Freeman, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2011; Accession 2011-A-062
  - American Prizes
    - Percival Wood Clement Prize
      - Levin, Joshua, "Walter Lippmann and His Jewish Problem;" advisor: Paula Hyman, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        This essay was also awarded the American Jewish Congress Prize in Judaic Studies.
      - Park, Katherine Jina, "The Other Baby Boom: Korean Adoption During the Cold War, 1951-1962;" advisor: Kariann Yokota, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - George Washington Egleston Prize
      - Olivarius, Kathryn Meyer, "Panic! on the Yazoo: Land Pirates, King Cotton, and the Lynchings of Madison County;" advisor: Edward Rugemer, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Andrew D. White American Prize
      - Ellis, Richard Aaron, " Christianity Today and the Six Day War: Biblical Prophecy and the Return of Christian Zionism, 1967-1971;" advisor: Jennifer Van Vleck, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Blancato, Lynda Cathryn, "A Leviathan Among Canoes: James G. Swan's Collection of Northwest Coast Artifacts for the Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition of 1876;" advisor: Kariann Yokota, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Addison Porter American History Prize
      - Breidbart, Samuel Ross, "The Development of Neoconservatism as a Reaction to John V. Lindsay's Urban Liberalism: An Essay on the Invention of an Ideology in New York City During the 1960s;" advisor: Daniel Kevles, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Edwin W. Small Prize
      - Cohen, Haley Brynne, "Paved with 'Good' Intentions: A Missionary Son and the Road to Hawaiian Annexation;" advisor: Jay Gitlin, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Moldovan, Jessica Alkaly, "History's Exiles: Viennese Refugees in New York and the Illusion of Assimilation;" advisor: Jay Gitlin, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        This essay was also awarded The Steere Prize in Women's and Gender Studies.
  - European Prizes
    - Winifred Sturley Prize
      - Fishman, Edward Benjamin, "History as Nemesis: Britain, German Unification, and the European State System, 1870-1875;" advisor: Adam Tooze, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Kim, Christina Kyung-Eun, "A Colonial Counterfactual: The Early Problems of the Assam Company, 1839-1849;" advisor: Timothy Guinnane, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Andrew D. White European Prize
      - Merriman, Christopher, "'Unwavering Patriots': Sacrifice, Coercion and the Contested Legacy of the FLN Soccer Team;" advisor: Bruno Cabanes, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Also received the Robert D. Gries Prize for the rest of the world.
      - Garcia, Deborah Quynh Nhu, "D.W. Winnicott and the Effect of the Evacuation on British Psychoanalysis;" advisor: Bruno Cabanes, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Rest of the World Prizes
    - Robert D. Gries Prize
      - Merriman, Christopher, "'Unwavering Patriots': Sacrifice, Coercion and the Contested Legacy of the FLN Soccer Team;" advisor: Bruno Cabanes, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Also received the Andrew D. White European Prize.
    - Max Bildner Prize
      - Serventi-Gleeson, Molly, "Repression and Reproductive Rights: The History of Abortion in Chile and the Legacy of Dictatorship;" advisor: Gilbert Joseph, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Fuhrer, Zachary Ross, "An Iron Road of Dependence: Consequences of 'Drought Relief' in Late-Nineteenth Century Ceará, Brazil;" advisor: Stuart Schwartz, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Andrew D. White Rest of the World Prize
      - Alter, Benjamin Dylan, "No War, No Peace: Attritional War and Diplomacy in the Middle East, 1967-1973;" advisor: Adam Tooze, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Sokoloff-Rubin, Emma Rachel, "'Pero Pa Mi Era Otra Cosa': Contested Memories of Pinochet's Chile;" advisor: Gilbert Joseph, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Outside Department Prizes
    - David Potter Prize (from Beinecke Rare Book Library)
      - Chandler, Thomas, III, "The National Media during the Georgia and California Gold Rushes: Depictions of Native Americans and Their Effect on Public Perception;" advisor: John Mack Faragher, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Walter McClintock Prize (from Beinecke Rare Book Library)
      - Tjemsland, Allison, "Indians, Gaming, and the Collapse of Federal Acknowledgment in Connecticut;" advisor: Alyssa Mt. Pleasant, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Wolfgang Leonhard Prize (from Yale Center for International and Area Studies)
      - Convey, Ian Alexander, "The Strength of the Sword is in the Arm that Wields it: The Stalinist Regime's Reconstruction of Pre-Soviet Historical Figures, 1934-45;" advisor: Paul Bushkovitch, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2012; Accession 2012-A-095
  - American prize winners
    - Andrew D. White American Prize
      - Dethlefs, Thomas, "Tear Gas and the Politics of Lethality: A Clouded Vision;" advisor: Bill Rankin, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Rosenthal, Adrienne Isobel, "Cook's Crusade: The Story and Significance of Constance Cook and the 1970 New York Abortion Bill;" advisor: Rebecca Tannenbaum, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Edwin W. Small Prize
      - Joseph, Matthew, ""Keepers of Song, Keepers of Tradition" Race and the Social Reproduction of Mississippi Hill Country Blues;" advisor: Jay Gitlin, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Johnson, Layne, "Yale College as a "little temple" Timothy Dwight, the Revival of 1802, and an Evolving Relationship between Liberalism and Religion;" advisor: Joanne B. Freeman, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - John Addison Porter American History Prize
      - Garcia, Victoria Gilcrease, "Narcotics Smuggling Between El Paso and Juarez from 1890-1950: The Forgotten Story of Ignacia Jasso;" advisor: Stephen Pitti, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - European prize winners
    - Winfred Sturley Prize
      - Hess, Alexandra, "The Prosecution of Women for Sexual Offenses in Early Modern England 1580-1640: "Neither a Fornicator nor an Adulterer Be";" advisor: Keith Wrightson, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Andrew D. White European Prize
      - Sprague, Ian F., "Revisiting Tolpuddle: A Critique of the TUC Narrative;" advisor: Keith Wrightson, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rest of the world prizes
    - Max Bildner Prize
      - Haas, Katherine, "Truth, Trials, Transition: The Meaning of Justice in Post-Dirty War Argentina;" advisor: Gilbert Joseph, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Robert D. Gries Prize
      - Outka, Jacqueline, "The Zar Ceremony in Egypt, 1865-1940: Competing Visions of the Role of Religion and the Necessity of Modernization;" advisor: Alan Mikhail, 2012
    - Andrew D. White Rest of the World Prize
      - Orazem, Kate, "The Female Circumcision Controversy and the Politization of Kiluyu Women;" advisor: Daniel Magaziner, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Winner of the Lily Rosen Prize - Awarded by Women's Gender and Sexuality Studies, 2012.
  - Outside Department prize winners
    - Henry K. Hayse Award by Ethnicity, Race, and Migration
      - Barrows, Jennifer, "Operation Babylift and the Memories of the Vietnam War: Rescuing Orphans, Raising America;" advisor: Mary Lui, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Applebaum Prize - University Library's Government Documents Collection
      - Crawford, Connor, "'Missionaries of ordered liberty': U.S. Colonial Sponsoship of Self-Government in the Wake of the Spanish-American War 1899-1904;" advisor: Patrick O. Cohrs, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2012-2013; Accession 2013-A-083
  - American prize winners
    - Percival Wood Clement Prize
      - Broach, Sophie Pennington, "Attacking the Roots of the Heroin Epidemic: The Failures of U.S.-Supported Herbicide Spraying of Opium Poppy Fields in Burma"; advisor: Paul Sabin (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - John Addison Porter Prize
      - de La Bruyere, Max Chopin, "It Would Be Embarrassing to Us: Mackenzie King, Canada, and Jewish Refugees, 1934-1939"; advisor: Jay Gitlin (Box 1, Folder 2)
        The author was also the recipient of the Canadian Studies Prize.
      - Harada, Megan Yoke, "Beauty and the Brain: The Aestheticization of Medicine at Yale's Cushing Center"; advisor: Joanna Radin (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Hawbaker, Luke, "All the Annals of Cruelty: The Stories, Scars, and Legacy of the Guerilla War in Kansas and Missouri"; advisor: John Mack Faragher (Box 1, Folder 4)
        The author was also the recipient of the David Potter Prize.
      - Rogers, Hilary Eileen, "The Reproductive and Racial Politics of Planned Parenthood in Black Communities, 1966-1974"; advisor: Naomi Rogers (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The George Washington Egleston Prize
      - Kemper, David, "Pericles' New York: Nelson Rockefeller, Edward Logue, and the Urban Development Corporation, 1968-1973"; advisor: Jay Gitlin (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Edwin W. Small Prize
      - Monsky, Harrison Weis, "Who's Afraid of the Weathermen? The Bureau on Trial, 1966-1981"; advisor: Beverly Gage (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Zhuang, Jasmine, "The Screen is only the Half Story: Minorities' Fight for Civil Rights in Hollywood"; advisor: Mary Lui (Box 1, Folder 8)
        The author was also the recipient of the Henry K. Hayase Prize.
  - European prize winners
    - Winifried Sturley Prize
      - Naegele, Ela A., "Bs'd Jurists of all Middle-European Countries Unite! On the German Idea of a Middle-European Law During World War I"; advisor: James Q. Whitman (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Smith, Rebecca, "Confessions in the Sermons of Three English Manuscripts, circa 1215-1350"; advisor: Paul Freedman (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rest of the World prize winners
    - Max Bildner Prize in Latin America
      - Gelbort, Hannah Elise, "The Developmental Trajectory of Nicaraguan Liberation Theology: From Impetus to Victim of the Sandinista Revolution"; advisor: Gilbert Joseph (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Soames, Teodoro Assis, "Brazilians in Paris, 1919"; advisor: Adam Tooze (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Robert E. Gries Prize
      - Dlugoleski, Deirdre, "Al-Bruni's Eleventh Century Anthropology on India: The More and Legal Implications of Objectivity"; advisor: Valerie Hansen (Box 1, Folder 13)
        The author was also the recipient of the South Asian Senior Essay Prize.
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Rotblat, Cameron E., "The Demobilization and Repatriation of the Tiralleurs Senegalais after the First World War: From Front to Foyer"; advisor: Bruno Cabanes (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Outside History prize winners
    - Williams Prize
      - Davis, Trevor, "Pure Land and the Social Order in Twelfth-Century China: An Investigation of Lonshu's Treatise on Pure Land"; advisor: Valerie Hansen (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Walter McClintock Prize
      - Tjemsland, Amanda, "The Unfulfilled Recommendations for Improving Indian Student Health in Off-Reservation Boarding Schools in the United States, 1900-1969"; advisor: Naomi Rogers (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Howard Lamar Prize
      - Haras, Maria, "Envisioning Los Angeles in the L.A. Times the Topographical Imagination of Charles H. Owens"; advisor: John Mack (Box 2, Folder 18)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2013-2014; Accession 2015-A-020
  - American prize winners
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Beshar, Isabel, "A Tale of Mutating Theory: the Evolution of the Thrifty Genotype Hypothesis"; advisor: Joanna Radin (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Kenaston, Connor, "If the Men Don't Fight, the Women Will: Women and Gender Roles in the West Virginia Mine Wars"; advisor: John Mack Faragher (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Edwin W. Small Prize
      - Kronick, William, "We Should Not Be Moved: How Government Deafness Doomed Urban Renewal in Charlotte, North Carolina"; advisor: Jennifer Klein (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Paterson, Lindsay W., "Pernicious Foreigner or Friend? William F. Buckley Sr., An American Businessman in Revolutionary Mexico, 1908-1921"; advisor: Stuart Schwartz (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - George Washington Egleston Prize
      - Torgeson, Sarah, "Reconstruction Beauvoir: Place and Civil War Memory on the Post-Katrina Mississippi Gulf Coast"; advisor: Ryan Andre Brasseaux (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Addison Porter Prize
      - Coe-Scharff, Jonah, "New Roads in Leftist Thought: Dwight MacDonald Lewis Coser and Postwar Crisis of American Marxism"; advisor: Beverly Gage (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Godfrey, Cooper F., "Red Israel: U.S. State Department Fears of a Soviet-Aligned Jewish State, 1948-1953"; advisor: John Lewis Gaddis (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Percival Wood Clement Prize
      - Nethercut, Sophie, "Ring of Fire: African American Employees in the Midwestern Circus, 1880-1920"; advisor: John Mack Faragher (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - European prize winners
    - Andrew D. White European Prize
      - Woodford, Antonia, "La Defense, 1958-1989, A Case Study in Postwar Urban Planning in the Paris Region"; advisor: Jon Merriman (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Winifred Sturley Prize
      - Coons, Margaret, "Princess to Protest: Sophia Duleep Singh and the Intersection of Women's Suffrage and Imperialism in Early Twentieth-Century Britain (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Rothberg, Rachel, "White Australia Resurgent: The Rise and Fall of the Digger Spirit, 1915-1921"; advisor: Amanda Behm (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History of Science and Medicine prize winners
    - Levine, Nicholas, "The Dignity of Exact Science: Evangeline Adams, Astronomy, and the Professions of the Probable, 1890-1940"; advisor: Joanna Radin (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Folder not received.
  - Latin America, Africa, Asian and the Middle East prize winners
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Minh-Chau Le, Adrienne, "Women of French Indochina, 1920-1945: The Rise and Influence of the Modern Vietnamese Woman"; advisor: Valerie Hansen (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Teysir, Jimmitti, " The New Times and Ethiopia News: A Voice for Resistance During the Italian Occupation"; advisor: Robert Harris (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Max Bildner History Latin American Prize
      - Fein, Katherine, "The Boundaries of Her World: Mary Welsh Hemingway at the Finca Vigia"; advisor: Beverly Gage (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Sesser-Ginzberg, Sasha, "Reorganizing Judiasm: Anti-Semitism and its Legacy During the "Dirty War" in Argentina, 1976-1983"; advisor: Anne Eller (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Robert D. Gries Prize
      - Guardado, Maria, "The Latinization of American Baseball: El Toro and Fernandomania, 1981-1991"; advisor: Jay Gitlin (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Outside department prize winners
    - Hobbs, Nicole, "The U.N. and the Congo Crisis of 1960"; advisor: Robert Harms (Box 1, Folder 18)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2016; Accession 2017-A-025
  - American prize winners
    - Andrew D. White Prize
    - Edwin Small Prize
      - Lowenstein, Julie, "U.S. Foreign Policy and the Soviet-Afghan War: A Revisionist History;" adviser: Rosie Bsheer (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - George Washington Egleston Prize
    - John Addison Porter History Prize
      - Vishwanath, Vivek, "Transforming Primary Care: How Multiphasic Health Services Redefined Care Delivery at Kaiser Permanente, 1948-1973;" adviser: John Harley Warner (Box 1, Folder 4)
        This essay was also the recipient of the History of Science and Medicine Rosen/Klein Prize.
    - Percival Clement Prize